<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.alper-han.CrossMacro</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>CrossMacro</name>
  <developer id="io.github.alper-han">
    <name>Alper Han</name>
  </developer>
  <summary>Cross-platform Mouse and Keyboard Macro Automation Tool</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      CrossMacro is a powerful cross-platform mouse and keyboard macro recording and playback tool.
      It supports recording inputs, text expansion, and playing them back with adjustable speed and looping.
      Works on Linux (Wayland/X11), Windows, and macOS.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Record and replay mouse movements, clicks, and keyboard events</li>
      <li>Text Expansion support for productivity</li>
      <li>Cross-platform support (Linux Wayland/X11, Windows, macOS)</li>
      <li>Global hotkeys for control</li>
      <li>Adjustable playback speed and loop mode</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">CrossMacro.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/alper-han/CrossMacro</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/alper-han/CrossMacro/issues</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Recording Tab - Record mouse and keyboard macros</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alper-han/CrossMacro/v1.3.1/screenshots/recording-tab.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Playback Tab - Play recorded macros with customizable settings</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alper-han/CrossMacro/v1.3.1/screenshots/playback-tab.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Files Tab - Manage saved macro files</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alper-han/CrossMacro/v1.3.1/screenshots/files-tab.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Text Expansion Tab - Create text shortcuts</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alper-han/CrossMacro/v1.3.1/screenshots/text-expansion-tab.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Settings Tab - Configure application preferences</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alper-han/CrossMacro/v1.3.1/screenshots/settings-tab.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.3.1" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>Version 1.3.1 - Native AOT compilation, major CLI performance optimizations, and Linux uinput stabilization fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Native AOT compilation support for CLI and UI packages, eliminating the .NET runtime dependency and dramatically reducing binary size, startup latency, and memory footprint.</li>
          <li>Optimized Linux virtual uinput device creation and stabilization using dynamic sysfs and ioctl calls, dropping sequential run delays.</li>
          <li>Optimized CLI startup by lazily evaluating capability probes and conditionally bypassing profile initialization, saving multiple redundant disk I/O operations on macro runs.</li>
          <li>Fixed a desktop entry filename casing issue across Linux packages to ensure standard application launcher compliance.</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential race condition (ENOENT) during evdev hardware device scanning when a temporary virtual uinput node is destroyed.</li>
          <li>Replaced the IsCapturing boolean with EditorCaptureMode enum in the UI editor to support rich macro recording states.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.0" date="2026-06-27">
      <description>
        <p>Version 1.3.0 - Screen-reading support, profile management, and input simulation improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added pixelcolor, waitcolor, and pixelsearch commands for color-based automation.</li>
          <li>Added built-in color picker and region capture controls for editor actions.</li>
          <li>Added support for native screen capturing backends.</li>
          <li>Added profile management to easily save, load, and switch configuration profiles.</li>
          <li>Added Fast and Compatible (Key-by-Key) method selector for Direct Typing text expansion to resolve character skipping.</li>
          <li>Added scheduler safeguards to prevent burst-firing of macros after system stalls.</li>
          <li>Improved Linux AppImage and Flatpak diagnostics to reliably detect missing input recording permissions upfront.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.1" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Version 1.2.1 - Multiline text expansion editing and updated GNOME Shell integration metadata.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added multiline text input and expansion support for text expansion entries and editor text actions.</li>
          <li>Added GNOME Shell 50 and 51 extension metadata support for newer GNOME environments.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2026-05-18">
      <description>
        <p>Version 1.2.0 - Linux coordinate playback, diagnostics, input reliability, and package runtime improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved Linux coordinate recording and playback with clearer absolute and relative coordinate handling.</li>
          <li>Expanded Linux daemon, socket, input backend, and doctor diagnostics with clearer startup notifications and troubleshooting details.</li>
          <li>Improved direct input capture edge cases, unavailable backend reporting, horizontal scroll recording, and stale daemon event handling.</li>
          <li>Added Niri keyboard layout detection for better Wayland desktop integration.</li>
          <li>Improved Linux package runtime reliability, including AppImage ICU bundling and hardened Arch daemon installation.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-05-05">
      <description>
        <p>Version 1.1.0 - Better editor workflows, smoother text expansion, randomized timing controls, stronger Linux integration, and more reliable packages.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added minimized startup, loaded macro playlists, editor filtering, multi-select controls, clearer toolbar actions, bundled icons, and more reliable editor selection behavior.</li>
          <li>Added clipboard-free text expansion, faster direct typing, safer paste insertion, and improved clipboard behavior across native sessions, Flatpak, and X11.</li>
          <li>Added randomized playback loop delays, schedule intervals, and shortcut repeat delays.</li>
          <li>Improved localization coverage for tabs, editor text, runtime states, placeholders, and language settings.</li>
          <li>Improved Linux support with Niri and COSMIC detection, batched input simulation, stronger permission handling, clearer setup guidance, and GNOME warning replay.</li>
          <li>Improved existing Flatpak integration with better host clipboard handling and cleaner build inputs.</li>
          <li>Improved CLI and headless automation with cleaner JSON output and more reliable daemon detection.</li>
          <li>Improved release packaging with stricter validation, refreshed package metadata, Avalonia 12, and compact portable Windows packages.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-03-28">
      <description>
        <p>Version 1.0.1 - Major Linux workflow improvements for scripting and Wayland environments.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a Linux mutex contention issue that could cause intermittent daemon synchronization failures.</li>
          <li>Added Wayfire Wayland compositor support for absolute pointer position integration.</li>
          <li>Added the current-position action for using live cursor coordinates in automation flows.</li>
          <li>Expanded the script engine with structured control flow: if, for, while, continue, and break.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.9" date="2026-03-09">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.9.9 - Improved Linux packaging reliability and refreshed application metadata.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.8" date="2026-03-01">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.9.8 - Added Flatpak support with Wayland compatibility.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2026-01-10">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.9.0 - Major update with Macro Editor and Themes support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.4" date="2026-01-03">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.8.4 - Bug fixes and improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.8.2 - Fixed daemon service path and Polkit configuration issues.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.8.1 - Bug fixes and improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2025-12-29">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.8.0 - Added Shortcuts and Scheduling features.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.2" date="2025-12-25">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.7.2 - Native Wayland Integration, UI Refinements, and Core Fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2025-12-25">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.7.1 - Bug fixes and improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2025-12-24">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.7.0 - Added macOS platform support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2025-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.6.1 - Added automatic GitHub update checking and notification support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2025-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>Version 0.6.0 - Improved daemon architecture and packaging.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
